<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tags | Dark Matter in Cyberspace]]></title>
  <link href="http://leetschau.github.io/blog/categories/tags/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://leetschau.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-02T16:10:00+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://leetschau.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Li Chao]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[leetschau@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy, Tag and Branch of Subversion]]></title>
    <link href="http://leetschau.github.io/blog/2013/08/30/180938/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-30T18:09:38+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://leetschau.github.io/blog/2013/08/30/180938</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tag and branch are the same from the point of view of svn server. They are both the &ldquo;copy&rdquo; operation (this is why they use the same menu item in TortoiseSVN, they are actually the &ldquo;svn copy&rdquo; command). Copy operation of svn server will create a link to original revision. So create tag or branch will not double the disk space usage. The disk space usage is actually related with how many files are modified based on a specific revision.</p>

<p>What is the difference of tag and branch? When you create a &ldquo;tag&rdquo;, you mean you will save this link at a &ldquo;baseline area&rdquo; where it&rsquo;s prohibited to do checkout-modify-checkin operation. On the contrary, if you create a &ldquo;branch&rdquo;, you will do checkout-modify-checkin operation in the future for new feature development or bug fix.</p>

<p>Use &ldquo;svn help copy&rdquo; for explanations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add Tags to Files With Xplorer2]]></title>
    <link href="http://leetschau.github.io/blog/2011/10/27/152904/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-27T15:29:04+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://leetschau.github.io/blog/2011/10/27/152904</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Win7 nowadays supports adding tags to files, and sorting/displaying files according to tags. However, only documents created by Office or image files support adding tags, while my favorite tag-arranged files are pdfs and archives (zip, rar, iso, etc). So this nested functionality of win7 can not satisfy me. Meanwhile, TotalCommander can add comments to files, but this functionality is insignificant, because these comments are stored in a separated file, which means if the target file is copied/moved to another place, comments will be lost.</p>

<p> Today I find this longing functionality in Xplorer2, which only works under NTFS format. Firstly you can add comments(here I use it as tags) to any kinds of files by selecting this file and [Action->Set comments]. Then you can search or select files with a particular tag as follow:</p>

<p> Open the find files window: ctrl+f;</p>

<p> Add a new rule in the “Additional Rules” frame;</p>

<p> In “Rule definition” panel, select “Comment” from “Property &amp; description” drop-down list, and specify the tags in the textbox beneath “Text Settings”;</p>

<p> Bingo!</p>

<p> For more details see &ldquo;Attaching comments to selected items&rdquo; of Xplorer2&rsquo;s documents.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
